Guide to the School of Education, Health, Nursing, and the Arts Professions (SEHNAP) Senior Theses 1950-1989 RG 26.0
New York University, Publisher
Records of School of Education, Health, Nursing, and the Arts Professions (SEHNAP): Senior Theses1950-1989
RG 26.0
6 linear feet
New York University
This collection consists of theses written by students in the School of Education, Health, Nursing, and the Arts Professions from the years 1950-1989.
Provenance
Details regarding the transfer of these materials are not available.
Access Restrictions
Materials may be restricted due to FERPA regulations. Contact the University Archives for specific information regarding access to these records.
Historical/Biographical Note
The New York University School of Education was founded in 1890 as the School of Pedagogy; it was renamed the School of Education in 1921, and thereafter called the School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions (SEHNAP) from 1974 to 1994.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of theses written by students in the School of Education, Health, Nursing, and the Arts Professions from the years 1950-1989. They are arranged in one series, neither in alphabetical or chronological order. The title and author's name are both found in the "Description" field. The theses are bound unless noted in brackets after the title (for example: [envelope]). In some instances, two copies of a theses are represented by one entry and noted in brackets after the title (for example: [quantity: 2]).
Arrangement
The collection is unprocessed and materials remain in original order. Theses are listed by author and title.
The files are grouped into 1 series.
Access Points
Subject Organizations:
New York University.; New York University. School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions; New York University. School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions. Division of Nursing
Subject Topics:
Nursing Study and teaching
Document Types:
Theses
Container List
  - An Investigation of the Relationship of Self-Disclosure, Interpersonal Dependency, and Life Changes to Loneliness in Young Adults by Noreen Elizabeth Mahon, 1981; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Comparison between Meditating Subjects and Non-Meditating Subjects on Time Experience and Human Field Motion by Janet Macrae [envelope], 1982; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Comparison between Meditating Subjects and Non-Meditating Subjects on Time Experience and Human Field Motion by Janet Macrae [envelope], 1982; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between Body-Cathexis, Personal Values and Attitudes Toward the Disabled, In First Year Baccalaureate Nursing Students by Helen Isabel MacRae, 1972; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - An Investigation of Nurses' Empathy and Critical Thinking Ability to Accuracy of Perception of Patients' Acute Pain Experiences by Linda F. Maciorowski, 1988; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sharing of Common Fears Between Mothers and Four and Five Year Old Children in Middle-Class Families by Colleen Lynch [envelope] [quantity:2], 1973; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Energy Wave Pattern Manifest in Red and Blue Light and Human Field Motion in Those With Visual Perception and With Blindness by Betty Ludomirski-Kalmanson, 1984; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Relation of Ethnicity and Ego Defensiveness of Female Registered Nurses to Their Attitudes Toward Ethnically Similar and Different Patients by Kem Betty Louie, 1983; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Relationship Between the Environmental Energy Wave Frequency Pattern Manifest in Red Light and Blue Light and Human Field Motion in Adult Individuals With Visual Sensory Perception and Those With Total Blindness by Betty G. Ludomirski, 1984; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sharing of Common Fears Between Mothers and Their Eleven Year-Old Children in Middle-Class Families by Suzanne Lego [envelope] [quantity:2], 1971; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Perceived Body Space and Self-Esteem in Adult Males With and Without Chronic Low Back Pain by Phyllis Lisanti [envelope], 1986; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Relationship Between Alcohol Consumption, Satisfaction and Experienced Control Among Women by Carolyn R. Lansberry, 1980; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Separation Anxiety, Conceptual Perspective Taking, and Social Competency in Nursery School Children in a Novel Situation by Arlene S. Kreinik, 1980; bar code #: 3 1142 04227151 3 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Psychoprophylaxis in Childbirth and Changes in Self-Concept of the Participant Husband and His Concept of His Wife byJacqueline Hott, 1972; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Variations in Speech, Blocking Agents in Speech, Decision Time, and Conflict in Marital Dyads by Patricia Hurley [envelope], 1978; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Risk Taking Characteristics, Belief in Internal-External Control, Emotional Reactivity, and the Lethality of the Suicide Plan in Women Who Have Attempted Suicide by Hanna M. Jacobson, 1973; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - How Can The Technique of Taking Temperatures At Sea View Hospital Be Improved? By Gerard Jakobi, 1950; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Perception of Power, Sex-Role Identity, and the Coping Patterns of Women by Carol Joyce, 1984; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Relationship Between Auditory Stimulation and the Developmental Behavior of the Premature Infant by Violet Katz, 1970; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Relationship Between the Type of the Child's Death Whether Anticipated or Unexpected and the Jordanian Mother's Grief Responses by Inaam Abdulla Khalaf, 1989; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Anxiety, Preferred Conversational Distance and Subjective Future Life Span by Elsa Kissel, 1976; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The Relationship Between Perceptual Reactance and the Preferred Rates of Speech and Gait by Penelope M. Klatell, 1975; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - An Abstract of the Relationship of Nurse-Patient Agreement on the Importance of Outcomes to Patient Satisfaction and Length of Stay by Christine Tassone Kovner, 1985; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Separation Anxiety, Conceptual Perspective Taking, and Social Competency in Nursery School Children in a Novel Situation by Arlene S. Kreinik [envelope], 1980; bar code #: 3 1142 04227152 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Self Concept, Field Dependence-Independence, and Judgment of Duration by Mary K. Harrison, 1982; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - An Investigation of Maternal Stress in Primigravidas as a Factor in the Production of Neonatal Pathology by Florence S. Downs, 1964; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Relation Between A Change in Social Routine and Fluctuations in Blood Pressure and Temperature by Marjorie G. Baker, 1974; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - An Investigation of Maternal Stress in Primigravidas as a Factor in the Production of Neonatal Pathology by Florence S. Downs [paperback], 1964; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Relationship of Mystical Experience, Differentiation, and Creativity in College Students by W. Richard Cowling III, 1983; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Speech Rate, Preferred Listening Rate of Speech and Perception of Time by Marie Boguslawski, 1975; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mnemonic Strategies and Parent Recall of Principles of Early Childhood Development by Anne DuVal Frost, 1987; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Relationship Between Appraisal of Adjustment Required by Reported Daily Life Events, Physical Symptoms and Temperature Range by Catherine A. Cassidy, 1975; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Menopausal Stage, Current Life Change, Attitude Toward Women's Roles, and Perceived Health Status in Middle-Aged Women by Nancy Sharts Engel, 1983; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - An Abstract of Pica, Hemaglobin, and Prematurity and Perinatal Mortality by Beverly Norine Dunston, 1961; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - A Study to Formulate Principles of Nursing Pertaining to Rehabilitation Which Underlie Professional Nursing Practice by Edith A. Schmitt, 1962; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between An Abrupt One Hour Shift in the Social Routine and the Extent and Duration of Blood Pressure and Temperature Changes in Young Women by Geraldene Felton, 1968; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between An Abrupt One Hour Shift in the Social Routine and the Extent and Duration of Blood Pressure and Temperature Changes in Young Women by Geraldene Felton [envelope], 1968; bar code #: 3 1142 04227153 9 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Relationship of Time Experience, Creativity Traits, Differentiation and Human Field Motion by Helen M. Ference, 1979; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - An Investigation of Patient Mood as a Function of the Social Climate on Nursing Units and Patient Locus of Control by Marianne Flood, 1986; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Development of an Instrument For Assessing Perceptions of Self-Image and the Relation of Field Dependence/Independence, Amount of Weight Loss, Sex, and Perceptions of Self-Image in Individuals Who Have Lost Weight by Virginia Elaine Gallaspy, 1980; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Relationship-differentiation of Self, Complementary Psychological Need Patterns, and Marital Conflict, 1984; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - The Effects of the Individual, the Interaction and the Measurement Partner on the Measurement of Conversational Distances in Young Adult Women by Effie Sherman Hanchett [quantity: 2], 1974; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - An Investigation of the Relationship Between Self Concept, Field Dependence-Independence, and Judgment of Duration by Mary K. Harrison, 1982; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - A Study of the Relationship of Total Nursing Hours to the Fatality Rate in a Specific Premature Unit by Helena Antosh and Eileen Hasselmeyer, 1955; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - An Investigation of the Effects of Therapeutic Touch on Anxiety of Hospitalized Patients by Patricia Heidt, 1979; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between Level of Activation, Body Temperature and Interpersonal Conflict in Family Relationships by Carol Noll Hoskins, 1978; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Level of Activation, Temperature and Interpersonal Conflict in Family Relationships by Carol Hoskins, 1978; bar code #: 3 1142 04227154 7 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Dependence and Anxiety in Male Patients Following Surgery by June Simmonds Rothberg, 1965; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between Physical-Physiological Activity and Infants' Growth and Development by Luz S. Porter, 1966; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Food Iron Intake and Hemoglobin Levels in Gravidae by Lillian Runnerstrom, 1963; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Relationship Between Active Sleep and Developmental Abilities in Infants Residing in Foundling Institutions by Jessie Mae Pepper, 1978; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Relationship Between Patterns of Acknowledgment in Parent-Child Communication and the Child's Exploratory Behavior and Self-Differentiation by Ruth A. O'Brien, 1978; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Relationship Between Knowledge and Perception of Registered Nurses and Their Potential For Meeting the Needs of Alcoholics as Perceived by Tubercular Alcoholic Veterans by Pearle G. Morrison, 1965; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Mothers' General Fearfulness, Their Daughters' Locus of Control and General Fearfulness in the Daughter by Sally Miller [envelope] [quantity: 2], 1974; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Relationship of the Duration of the Sleep State, Level of Wakefulness and Frequency of Beyond Waking Experience by Fay A. Miller [envelope], 1984; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - The Relationship of Sleep, Wake, and Beyond Waking Experiences: Rogers' Concept of Sleep/Wake by Fay A. Miller [envelope], 1984; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Civil Liability and Nursing by Beulah Eglantine Miller, 1957; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - The Relationship Between Maternal and Musical Auditory Stimulation and the Developmental Behavior of Premature Infants by Gail B. Malloy, 1974; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Relationship Between Temperature Rhythm, Activation Rhythm and Mood Rhythm in Women by Mahassen Mansour [envelope], 1983; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Relationship Between Body Temperature Rhythm, Level of Activation Rhythm and Mood Rhythm in Women by Mahassen M. Mansour, 1983; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Relationship Between Maternal and Musical Auditory Stimulation and the Developmental Behavior of Premature Infants by Gail B. Malloy, 1974; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Hyperactivity in Children and Perception of Short Wavelength Light by Violet Malinski [envelope], 1980; bar code #: 3 1142 04227155 4 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Nurses Empathy for Patients' Experience of Post-Operative Pain as a Function of the Degree of Humanism in the Nursing Environment, the Patient's Age, and Length of Time Since Surgery by Margarete Lieb Zalon, 1988; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between Depression and Interpersonal Conflict in the Postpartum by Edith H. Anderson, 1963; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - A Study to Formulate Principles of Nursing Pertaining to the Maintenance and Promotion of Health Which Underlie Professional Nursing Practice by Ruth Elizabeth Anderson, 1963; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Relationship of Anxiety Changes and an Information-Giving Experience by Charlotte Marie Keller, 1965; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Change in Attitudes of Basic Nursing Students by Beatrice Ruth Brooks, 1959; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - An Investigation of Total Nursing Needs in Two General Hospitals and One Cancer Hospital as a Basis for Determining the Kind and Amount of Nursing Personnel Necessary to Meet These Needs by Rosemary Elizabeth Bouchard, 1959; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - An Investigation of Needs of Released Mental Patients on Tranquilizing Drugs in Relation to Recommending A Public Health Nursing Follow-Up Program by Ida Gelber, 1957; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - A Study of the Relationship Between an Abrupt One Hour Shift in the Social Routine and the Extent and Duration of Blood Pressure and Temperature Changes in Young Women by Geraldene Felton, 1968; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Social Class and Interpersonal Interaction in Young Children by Phyllis Adeline Putnam, 1963; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - A Study to Formulate Principles of Nursing Pertaining to Nursing Diagnosis and Nursing Therapy Which Underlie Professional Nursing Practice by Dorothy McMullan, 1962; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - The Relationship Between Sociability and Personal Space Preferences Among College Students in the Morning and in the Afternoon by Janet A. Rodgers, 1971; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - The Relations Among Measures of State Anxiety, Critical Thinking Ability and Judged Duration of Individuals During and After a Disruptive Life Event by Diane W. Scott, 1980; bar code #: 3 1142 04227156 2 (Box 6, Folder 12)